







Summary

Jump to Section

Result-oriented Professional with over 3.1 years of experience in Software Development, Application Programming, Web Development, Requirement Gathering, Application Support, Technical Support, Network Administration, Incident Management, Java, Spring Boot, Java Script, Apache Tomcat.

Work Experience

Cognizant Technology Solutions as Associate Developer

Dec 2017 to Till Date

Project: Pfizer Digital Transformation-Solution Delivery

Client: Pfizer

Pfizer Digital Team develops use case in ThingWorx, and Java based applications which provides real-time visibility into various operations such as Energy Consumption, tracking defects, Monitoring the life cycle of a product and many more to identify ways to improve Operating Efficiency by a reduction of availability losses.

Project Profile

Project 5: Defect Tracking Tool

Responsibility: Develop Application using ThingWorx, Creating Microservices, Technology: SQL Server, IOT (ThingWorx), PostgreSQL, JavaScript, CSS, Spring Boot,

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

SSRS, Report Builder, SSDT

Team Size: 8

Duration: May 2019 - Till date

Role: Lead Developer

The solution provides the ability to digitize and automate various inspection process such as Automatic inspection, Semi-Automatic inspection, Manual Inspection and AQL Inspection which are processed on a batch in a manufacturing plant. Batch Details from external database is moved into SQL Server and the inspection is processed on those batches. Batch Results are verified by QA to proceed the batch to further stages. Developed ThingWorx Mashups/Services, Microservices, designed database structure, written queries/Store Procedure's with database connectivity that could replace the spreadsheet adopted by Defect Tracking team.

- As a Team member was responsible for
 * Worked as SME and lead for Defect Tracking project
- * Requirement Analysis & Design.
- * Connecting with multiple teams on finalizing the requirements.
- * Creating Micro Services that communicates with UI
- * Working on database design.
- * Developed Custom Extensions.
- * Development of Queries/ Store Procedure's
- * Development of individual modules for application using ThingWorx
- * Responsible for Application Deployment and Run phase

Project 4: TIR TOR

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Responsibility: Develop Application using ThingWorx

Technology: SQL Server, IOT (ThingWorx), PostgreSQL, JavaScript, CSS,

SSRS, Report Builder, SSDT

Team Size: 3

Duration: May 2020 - Till date

Role: Developer

The Solution provides real-time visibility into various operations/process the batch goes through, to identify ways to improve Operating Efficiency by configuring various process parameters and managing alerts. Developed ThingWorx screens/Mashups with database connectivity that could replace the spreadsheet adopted by the Fluconazole Team to monitor critical process parameters. Data from external Catalyst database is moved to SQL. Performs KPI Calculations using the Data extracted in SQL Database.

As a Team member was responsible for

- * Requirement Analysis & Design.
- * Connecting with multiple teams on Finalizing the requirements.
- * Working on database design.
- * Development of application using ThingWorx.
- * Responsible for Application Deployment and Run phase.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Vellore Institute of Technology (VIT) in 2017

PG: Integrated PG (Software Engineering) from Vellore Institute of Technology (VIT) in 2017

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Introduction to Internet of Things ThingWorx Fundamentals Certification Azure Fundamentals ThingWorx Professional Curriculum for Developer

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
JAVA			
Spring Boot -Mcro services			
Java Script, React Basics			
MS SQL Server, Postgres			
HTML, CSS, JQUERY			
ThingWorx, Manufacture Apps			
Spring tool Suite			
Apache Tomcat			
TEAMFORGE			
SSRS, Report Builder, SSDT			

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
ENGLISH				
HINDI				
TELUGU				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.